[SOUND] Hi,
I'm going to discuss the first lecture,
A Brief Introduction to Data Mining.
We are going to briefly, discuss this
because the concept, is well understood.
And, if you want to know more, please
feel free to get into my chapter 1 of
the textbook, and you can,
you can read and get more details.
The first question I'm going to
ask you is, why data mining?
You probably say,
since I'm taking the course I know,
why I'm going to do data mining.
It's a very simple common sense concept.
We are living in a digitized society.
We are surrounded with big data,
or we say,
we are encountering the explosive
growths of the data.
The data ex, explosion problem has been
here, since computer comes to the stage,
especially with the web appearing with
lots of data collection tools appearing.
We're collecting lots of data.
First, we actually got the web and
the computer's rise to society.
The news, digital media,
social networks, e-commerce, and
you know, banking, you know, every corner
of society generate huge amount of data.
Even in science and engineering,
we got a remote sensing,
bioinformatics, scientific simulation and
many other domains.
They keep generate
tremendous amount of data.
So, people say we are drowning in data but
starving for knowledge.
Why?
Just because a lot of data we've
generated are unstructured.
The knowledge is deeply, buried inside.
If we do not have powerful
tools to mine such data,
it is impossible we can get
lots of benefit from such data.
So, data mining is a really a necessity.
So people say,
necessity is a mother of invention.
Data mining is a tool to automatically,
to do scalable analysis of massive am,
amount of data.
So this is a really needed technology.
So, what is data mining?
Most people based on my
understanding refer data mining,
as knowledge discovery from data.
Actually, the first KDD
workshop started in 1989,
was called Knowledge Discovery
in Databases.
But a few years later in 1995, when the
first KDD conference come to the stage,
they changed the title of the conference
to Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining.
So, data mining really become a popular
term, you know, even at that stage.
Okay?
So, for data mining,
most people thinking is
extraction of interesting patterns
of knowledge from massive data.
What is interesting patterns?
Usually the pattern could be non-trivial,
implicit, previous unknown,
potentially useful, or
ev, even actionable.
Okay.
But actually if you think.
Sit back and think a little.
Data mining is actually, a misnomer.
Why?
Because we think gold mining.
The gold mining is not, we got lots of
gold, or we mine something out of gold.
We actually got lots of sands, or ore.
We mine you know, sand,
and ore to get gold.
So to that extent,
more precisely, we should say,
we mine data,
actually we want to get knowledge.
So essentially,
it is knowledge mining from data.
But since data mining is a short term,
people say,
we are doing the mining process.
We are dealing with data, so data
mining becomes a very popular term, so
people understand that we are doing
knowledge mining from data, so
there's no real ambiguity if we
call just it, as data mining.
But data mining, some people say, data
mining is essentially some, some other
fields, like machine learning, or pattern
recognitions, statistical database.
Actually, data mining is
a interdisciplinary field,
integrating many methods, and
develop a lot of new methods of its own.
So, we are going to
discuss this relationship.
In the next several slides.
Okay.
So let's look at this picture.
This picture, people call this one,
is a knowledge discovery process.
Essentially is we got from data,
actually data could be anywhere,
we drawn as a disk,
actually could be on the web,
could be a data streams,
could be fires as long, as is digitized.
We take the data from multiple sources.
We do data integration, data cleaning,
data normalization, or feature selection,
dimension analysis reduction.
All of these we call data integration and
data processing.
Okay, then we get integrated and
process data, which could be stored
in databases, data warehouses or
some or some other data repositories,
or even in the form of data streams.
Okay.
Then with such huge amount
of data in many cases,
people only interested in part of it.
So, we may need to do data
selection by using queries,
by using feature selection,
or any other methods.
Then, we perform data mining.
Data mining these functions,
we are going to discuss in
the next slides a little more.
Finally, we get patterns but
a pattern is not the final product,
because the pattern could be redundant,
pattern may not be quite meaningful.
So we still need to do pattern evaluation,
pattern selection, data pattern
interpretation, and data visualization.
Sometimes we found the pattern is not
what we need, that we can have a backward
process to redo the data mining, or you
calling some other data mining functions.
Finally, we develop a pattern,
we think they are valuable.
We present in a visual way, or
in a usable way that means we really
gotta patent information and knowledge.
Remember for these processes, we only say,
Data Mining is part of KDD process
of course, is most critical one.
Actually, data pre-processing
sometimes is also very critical,
takes a lot of efforts it will depends
on your application by the data mining.
For this course is a core
function we're going to study.
For Data Mining,
we can have a Multi-Dimensional View.
That means, data mining can be viewed
from multiple angles, for example to see,
from the data view, from knowledge view,
from methodologies view, and
from application point of view.
From data view, essentially, as we study
what kind of data we're going to mind?
Essentially, there are two kinds.
One, we called structured, and
semi-structured data, and
other is unstructured data.
The structured and semi-structured data
could come from relational databases,
object-relational databases,
data warehouses, or
even from transactions,
transaction databases.
Okay.
For unstructured data,
data can come from anywhere.
For example, from the web,
from text, news.
Okay.
Or from spatial,
spatiotemporal devices' sensors.
Or from cameras, like from mul,
you get multimedia data.
It could be from multiple sensors,
you get data streams, or
we get a biological sequences,
temporal data, time series data, and also,
recently, there are lots of network data.
For example, social networks, information
networks, web graphs, need to be mined.
So, essentially, since the data are of so
different kinds.
It creates lots of new challenges,
and problems for data mining.
Another view for
data mining is knowledge view.
Knowledge view, you essentially study,
what kind of knowledge to be mined.
For example, we may use different
methods to do data summary,
multidimensional aggregation,
const, getting data cubes.
Put in the data warehouse to do old lab,
online and a little bit processing.
This is one way to mine data.
Another way is we may look
at it to find patterns.
Like frequent patterns,
correlation, association, and
use such patterns in many other tasks,
or even implicitly.
Okay.
The third major task is classification,
and predictive modeling.
This many is we may get
some training data.
It could be labeled by experts.
Then we use this training
data we get models.
Using this model we can predict,
or label the new data.
Okay.
So this prediction,
we call this model construction and
prediction, as predictive modeling, so
classification and the predictive modeling
in many cases, they could be synonyms.
But if you got data, you do not
really have expert give you labors,
that means the data could be unsupervised.
Then this forms a cluster process.
Okay.
Clustering essentially, is trying to
group data to from different groups, or
different categories, or even hierarchies.
The online analysis is another task.
Essentially, it's to detect anomalies,
or rare events, and
label them outliers to pay
special attention out of it.
Okay.
And if you get a time evolving data,
like you get time,
as one of the dimension,
or one of the factors.
Okay.
Then we may want to find the trends,
or evolution.
So, trend and evolution analysis
is another data mining function.
And data mining as we just mentioned,
it come from many different discipline,
as a confluence of these disciplines,
it comes a new domain or
new field for data mining.
Of course, machine learnings statistics
pattern recognition feed data mining
a lot of useful,
interesting algorithms and methodologies.
But data mining, itself,
generates lots of new methods.
And new data mining hardware, and
meth, and methodologies as welle.
Plus visualization,
where will greatly help data mining,
or understand the mine patterns, or
understand the data to be mined.
In the meantime, Algorithms,
Database Technology, Distributed and
cloud computing will all play a very
important role in Data Mining development.
Finally, applications is
a driving force for data mining.
So there are very diverse applications.
You need to develop many, many
different kinds of Data Mining methods.
Finally, we look at the Application View.
We also know data mining has a lot
of Diverse Applications, for
example, mining textbooks.
Text data, mining the Web, doing Web
page classification, Web page ranking,
Weblog analysis,
recommendation systems to recommend a page
different Web pages or different products.
Okay, so
these are one kinds of Application.
But mining business data
like transaction data,
market analysis, market basket analysis,
fraud detection.
All of these attributes,
need lots of data mining measures.
Data mining actually also benefits
computer science quite a lot.
Data mining can help software
engineering to find bugs.
And help system engineering to
optimize their system performance.
Or can even you know,
help with computer vision, okay.
And mining biological and
medical data will be very useful.
For example, we get a exponential growth
of the biological data like gene,
protein, microarray data,
biological networks.
And data mining may play
a important role in it.
And also recently,
there are lots of social, and
information networks coming out.
Okay.
How to find their communities,
how to do information diffusion,
how to see the information
interacting within this networks,
is very interesting and very exciting.
Finally, I want to mention
invisible data mining.
Actually, data mining now play
a lot of important roles, but
you may not even know
data mining is in sight.
Kay?
For example, you do a web search.
'Kay.
There are Web page ranking,
Web page classification, web click
string analysis, or recommendations.
There are many, many data mining methods,
actually embedded in your clicks, okay?
To that extent, data mining can play
a very important role in our society,
you may not even sense it.
'Kay.
So to learn more about this introduction,
I recommend three books.
One is my own book on Concepts and
Techniques of Data Mining.
The second one is a recent
book published eh,
in Cambridge University Press by Zaki and
Meira.
It's a very, very nicely written book.
Pang-Ning Tan, Michael Steinbach,
and Vipin Kumar got a book,
they got a new edition on Introduction
to Data Mining, published in 2014.
Finally, I want to say, Charu Aggarwal eh,
and myself actually co-edited
a new book on Frequent Pattern Mining,
which is closely related to this course.
Because we are doing pattern
discovering data mining.
There are lots of known authors,
they contribute to different
chapters to this book.
Reflecting the current data of,
of our pattern mining.
So, you may really want to read it.
Thank you.
[MUSIC]