[SOUND]
Hi,
let's introduce the very
famous Apriori Algorithm.
This algorithm is that the first candidate
generation and test approach for
frequent pattern mining.
Okay.
It is a level-wise candidate
generation test approach.
Initially, the first time you
just scan the database once to
get frequent 1-itemset.
Then taking this frequent
1-itemset your going to
generate length-2 candidate itemsets.
The case iteration, you are going to
take a length-k frequent itemsets
to generate length-k
plus 1 candidate itemset.
Then you go against the database to
test these candidates generated and
to find the real frequent
k plus 1-itemsets.
Okay.
Every iteration you set k to k plus 1,
so you can go until no frequent
itemsets can be generated or
no candidate itemsets can be generated.
Okay.
Then after you exit from loop,
you just return all the frequent itemsets
that's derived, that's the algorithm.
Let's look at the pseudocode.
We set C sub k to be
the candidate itemset of size k.
F sub k to be the frequent
itemset of size k.
Initially, we just get a frequent
1-itemset, then we get into the loop.
Suppose the frequent k item set
is not empty, then we get in.
We use k's frequent item set to
generate k plus 1's candidate itemsets.
Then we go against the database
using the menu support to see,
which k plus 1 candidate
itemsets are frequent.
Okay.
We derive the frequent k plus 1-itemsets.
Then we reset k to k plus 1
until we get out of this loop,
we just return all the frequent k
itemsets for all the k's derived.
Okay?
Let's look at a concrete example, okay?
You'll look at this transaction database,
it contains only four transactions.
Okay.
The first scan, you just try to find
their support for every single itemset.
Okay.
Then we find D, the support is only 1,
so it's not frequent.
So then we just remove it, we get
a frequent 1-itemsets and their support.
Okay.
Then we use this to derive
the candidate 2-itemsets C sub 2,
then we scan the Again,
we find the real support Then we find
these two blue marker ones are infrequent,
we derive frequent 2-itemsets.
Then using frequent 2-itemsets, we derive
the frequent three candidate itemsets.
Remember, this why you
probably can't see a big cut.
Why?
Because you probably see A,
C, B, C are frequent.
You may think A, B, C could be candidate
itemset, but A, B is not frequent here.
So, A, B, C will not be derived.
So we only derive B, C, E.
Okay.
With another scan, we find it support two,
so it's frequent as well.
Then we find all the frequent,
one, two, three itemsets.
The concrete implementation actually
involve self-joining and pruning.
Self-joining goes like this.
Okay.
We've got abc, abd.
The first two are the same,
the third one is different.
So we generate this self-joined
generate this candidate set.
Okay.
The similar thing, we've got acd,
ace, the first two are just the same.
The third one, we get them together.
We get this candidate sets.
But okay, we may need a pruning process.
The pruning is pretty simple.
Before you count against the database,
you proceed for abcd.
This bcd is there, so
this is the candidate one.
But for acde, cde it is not in
the frequent three itemset.
So acd cannot be the candidate,
so it's pruned.
So that's the simple
way of self-joining and
the pruning, we can solve this problem.
Okay.
The final we get only one candidate sets,
abcd.
Lets look at the SQL Implementation of
this candidate set generation and test.
So we proceed the candidate
generation is essentially this.
Okay.
You perceive the self -joining,
how to do self-joining?
You will see the first pay minus 2,
they are identical.
Then the last one, k minus 1 item,
1 is smaller than the other,
we get it one candidate set.
Then for this candidate set,
we still need pruning.
The pruning, essentially to
check whether these subsets,
the k minus 1 subset, containing this one.
If s is not on f k minus 1,
then we just delete this
candidate from the candidate set, C sub k.
So this is a candidate generation, the key
step of SQL Implementation of app array.
[MUSIC]