[SOUND].
Hi.
In this lecture we're going to introduce
some basic concepts of pattern discovery.
We are going to discuss these
three issues in three sessions.
The first session we are going to discuss,
what is pattern discovery?
Why it is important.
To know why pattern
discovery is important,
we need to know what are the patterns,
okay?
Patterns actually are a set of items,
subsequences or
substructures that occur
frequently together in data sets.
We call these strongly correlated.
Patterns usually represent intrinsic and
important properties of data.
That's why pattern discovery is a process.
Try to uncover, try to mine
patterns from massive data sets.
It has many interesting applications.
For example, in transaction database,
you may want to find what kind of
products are often purchased together.
Then you can do some targeted marketing.
And for customers, you may want to study,
if a person buying an iPad,
what are likely other products he or
she is going to buy in the future?
Okay.
And even for
software engineering you may want,
based on the code segment analysis,
try to find copy-and-paste bugs.
For text analysis,
you may want to see what are likely
the keywords were form phrases.
Finding phrases may need
pattern mining as well.
So we can see pattern discovery
could be very important because it,
it is uncovered inherent
regularities in the data sets.
It forms the foundation for many things.
For example, associating
correlation causality analysis,
mining sequential structure patterns,
pattern analysis in spatiotemporal data,
multimedia data and stream data.
Even for classification, if we use
discriminative pattern-based analysis,
the classification could be more accurate.
And for cluster analysis,
pattern-based subspace clustering could
be an important direction for
cluster analysis.
So there's no wonder why we want
to study pattern discovery.
[MUSIC]