[NOISE] Now,
we're going to introduce another set
of importance concepts,
Closed patterns and Max-patterns.
Actually, in association rule mining,
or frequent pattern mining.
There's one challenge, is in many cases we
may generate too many frequent patterns.
Usually a long pattern will contain
a combinatorial number of sub-patterns.
Just give you one simple example,
suppose we get a transaction database,
it contains only two transactions.
T sub-1 and T sub-2.
For T sub-1, it contains only 50 items,
a sub-1 to a sub-50.
For transactions in T2, it contains
100 itemsets, a sub-1 up to a sub-100.
Suppose we set the minimum support,
the absolute minimum support is only 1,
that means everything is frequent.
Then how many frequent items it contains?
Let's have a try.
Okay.
So, for frequent 1-itemsets,
we have a1 occurs twice,
a2 occurs twice, up to a50 occurs twice.
Then a51 occurs only once,
up to a100 occurs only once.
Then, what about 2-itemsets?
Actually, 2-itemsets is all
the possible combinations of a1 to a2,
a1 to a3, up to a99 to a100.
You probably, can see
some are support two,
some support only one.
Then, we can go on and
on, up to 99-itemsets,
we [INAUDIBLE] get a1 to a sub-99,
the support is one.
It can chop one by one.
So, finally, you get a2,
a3 to a sub-100 support is 1.
Finally, we'll get a 100-itemset,
where support is only 1.
If we add all of these together,
that means 100 choose 1, 100 choose 2,
up to 100 choose 100 we'll get a huge
number 2 to the power of 100 minus 1.
That many sub-patterns.
This is a huge set for any computer,
it's too huge to compute or store.
Then how can we handle such a challenge?
Why interesting proposal is introduce
the concept of closed patterns?
What is closed pattern?
We say, X is closed if X is frequent, and
there exist no super-pattern
Y with the same support as X.
Just give you a simple example.
We look at the same transaction database,
like T1 and T2.
We still say is minimum support is 1.
So, how many closed patterns
does this transaction contain?
So, instead, of 2 to power 100 minus 1,
we actually find only 2.
A1, to a50 support is 2.
A1 to a100 support is 1.
You may say, wait, you may lose something.
Let's look at it, do you know a1 to a49?
Actually, it's contain here,
it must be support of 2.
Do you know a1 to a51?
it contains here, it support must be 1.
So you can see, you do not lose
anything because your guard
the concrete patterns,
which are the maximum close to 1.
In the meantime, you do not lose the
support information for any sub-patterns.
So to that extent,
we can say closed pattern in a lossless
compression of frequent patterns.
It does reduce the number of patterns but
does not lose the support information.
For example, you will still be
able to say, a sub-2 to sub-40.
The support is 2, a5, a51,
this item said support is 1.
Then let's look at another possible
compression called max-patterns.
Max-pattern, the definition
is very similar,
except it does not carry
the support anymore.
That means X is a max-pattern,
if X is frequent and
there exists no frequent super pattern Y,
which is a super pattern of X, and
we don't care to support anymore.
So the difference from
the close-pattern is we do
not care the real support of
the sub-patterns of a max-pattern.
Let's look at the transaction
database like this.
Okay.
We still say, minimum support is 1,
then how many max-patterns does
this transaction database contain?
Okay.
So, we will find only 1.
The reason is,
even a sub-1 to a sub-50 the support is 2.
But, remember we do not
care support any more.
For this a1 to 1 sub-50,
it does exist a super-pattern like this.
Okay.
Which is also frequent to that
extent is the further compression.
So, you only get a one pattern,
but it is a lossy compression
because we only know a sub-1
to a sub-40 is frequent.
But we will not know the real support
of a sub-1 to a sub-40 and many more.
So, you do lose a support information
of many frequent itemsets.
Okay.
To that extent in many applications,
mining close-patterns is more
desirable than mining max-patterns.
We are going to see this
in our future discussions.
Okay.
So for this lecture, we mainly,
give you four recommended readings.
The first one actually,
is a first time introduced frequent
patterns and association rules.
The second one,
is the first time introduced max-patterns.
The third one, is the first time
introduce the closed-patterns.
And the fourth one, actually is an
overview, give you overall, you know, this
field, how the frequent pattern mining
came, and how it evolves up to this stage?
Thank you.
[MUSIC]