[SOUND].
Let's first introduce some basic concepts.
Frequent patterns and associations rules.
We, first look at this
simple transaction example.
There are five transactions,
10 to 50 other transaction IDs.
And these are the sets of items.
They bought.
For example,
transaction ID 10 contains beer, nuts, and
diaper, which form an itemset
because this is a, a set of items.
And for this particular one, it is three
itemset because it contains three.
Items.
And for each item set,
you may have a concept of support.
Support means, in these transactions data
set, how many times does beer happen?
Like in this particular case,
there are three occurrences of
beer in this transaction data.
So the support can't appear as three.
But you also can use relative support,
that means the fraction
of the transactions.
For example,
there are a total of five transactions.
Three of them contains beers, so
the relative support is 3 over 5,
or you can say 60%.
So, we may see whether in
itemset X is frequent or not.
If X, the support of X,
pass a minimum support threshold.
For example, if we said the minimum
support threshold is 50%.
Then, we can see the frequent 1-itemset,
in this data set,
you will find there are 4, like,
beer, you can see there are, 3 cases,
the absolute support is 3,
the relative support is 3 over 5 is 60%.
Okay.
But for frequent 2-itemsets,
you may check it.
There, there's only one, okay?
Because there's beer and diaper,
they happen together 3 times out of 5.
That's why we get this.
But none of the other, you know,
itemsets, they pass this.
50% threshold.
So there's only 1.
And from the frequent itemsets we
can introduce an interesting rule,
Association Rule.
That implies for
example X implies Y simply says,
if people buying X,
what is the support and
confidence people will buy the itemset Y,
okay.
Then s is the support which
is the probability X and
Y contain together in this rule set, okay.
Then c is the confidence which
is a conditional probability.
That means, if the transaction contains X,
what is the probability
it also contains Y?
So, for this probability computation,
you can use support X union Y,
divided by support X.
That means, take the whole rule support,
divide by the left-hand side.
You may see this notion X unit Y.
This is a set unit.
But if you look at the Venn diagram.
Actually, connections containing
X could be this part.
Connection containing diaper
not beer is this part.
Diaper is this part.
Containing both actually
is their intersection.
Okay, the intersection of the events,
okay.
But for from itemset point of view.
Echo the transactions
containing both X and Y.
Both beer and diaper,
you will say this one work on.
That's why we use not X intersects Y,
but X union Y.
Okay, if you think that X is beer,
Y is diaper.
X intersects Y will be empty.
X union Y means it contains both.
Then, for association rule mining,
is actually try to
find all such rules which has minimum
support and confidence threshold.
We already know if we set
minimum support at 0.5, we'll
find these are the frequent 1-itemsets,
these are the frequent 2-itemsets.
From here, if we set minimum confidence
as 50%, we are going to derive
two association rules, because these
two rules if you use this computation.
Beer and Diaper and getting together is 3.
In here, okay.
Then, it's 60% because 3 over 5.
And if every time beer occurs,
you can see diaper also occur,
that's why the confidence is 100%.
But for diaper implies beer,
you probably can see the diaper
support is 4, beer support is 3.
So, that means there's only 75% of
probability the customer buying a diaper,
likely to buy beer.
Are their more rules in this one?
Actually if you check this, because
this is the only frequent two item set.
These two are the only
association rules that can be
generated from this transaction data.
[MUSIC]