[SOUND] Hi, I'm going to introduce you
another interesting pattern mining
approach called Pattern Growth Approach.
This approach is represented by
an interesting algorithm called FPGrowths.
Let's look at how this algorithm works.
The general idea is, first,
we find the frequent single items.
And then we partition the de,
database based on each such item.
Then we recursively grow frequent
patterns by doing the above.
Each or
recursively for each partition database,
also called conditional database.
To facilitate efficient processing, we
use a new data structure called FP-tree.
The whole mining can be
summarized as follows.
We recursively construct and
mine conditional FP-trees.
Until the resulting FP-tree is empty,
or until it contains only one path,
this single path will generate all
the combinations of its sub-paths,
each of which is a frequent pattern.
Let's look at a simple example.
For this connection database it
has only five connections each
contains a set of items.
So we can scan the database once,
find the single item frequent
pattern like the following.
Suppose the minimum support
is 3 we will be able to find.
The falling frequent single items.
Then we can sort
the frequent items based on
its support frequency in
descending order like this.
Based on this, we can construct a tree.
But first construct the header
following this order.
Then scan the database.
We can construct this tree as follows.
For example, okay if you look at the,
the first transaction,
it's f c a b m p, so we constructed
f c a b m p with only support as 1.
Then we get f c a b m,
we constructed this f c a b m.
And this power support
becomes 2 this need to be 1.
It, you know, one by one we
reconstruct the falling tree.
Then to mine this tree, we can use divide
and conquer and do it recursively.
We can do it like this.
Okay, for each such tree,
we can construct this pattern base, or
we call p's conditional pattern base,
m's conditional pattern base.
So let's look at how p's conditional
pattern base is constructed, okay?
So you probably can see, p.
Is the leaf of the note.
You want to look it up.
You get f, c, a, m.
The support is 2 because p occurs
together with this branch only twice.
That's why you get f c a m 2.
Then for the same reason.
You look at the other p, its cb
happens only once together with its p.
That's why it gets cb:1.
Okay.
Then if you want to look at m's
conditional database,
the philosophy you are thinking
the patterns having m but not.
Having p, because p all ready been taking
care by the p's conditional pattern base.
So you look at it,
m's conditional database.
Actually, you also look up.
You get fca.
So for, for this branch,
it'll occur twice.
That's why you get fca:2.
For the same reason you look at this m,
you get fcab:1, so you get fcab:1.
You can do this on and on.
Then with this you can get it to
transform the prefix pass of p.
Okay, then the remaining task is just
mine this conditional pattern base.
For this conditional pattern base,
we mine single item patterns,
we construct this FP-tree and
mine it recursively.
For example, for p's conditional
pattern base, you will get only c: 3.
The reason is f, a, m, and
b; they never occurred more than
three times, so they are out.
They are not frequent, you only get three.
Therefore, m's conditional pattern base,
you can see fca really occurs three times.
The b only occur once,
you, then you get a fca:3.
Then b's conditional pattern base,
you probably can none of
them actually pass a support
threshold of 3, so it's empty.
So let's just look at, of course,
you'll, you will get a and
a c's pattern base like the,
like f's 3 and fc:3.
Actually, for the single branch, you can
dump all the possible combinations there,
so for all three.
But if we just, look at the,
in the recursive way, how we can mine this
pattern-base, for this pattern-base,
you plug in c, you can say for a,.
Conditional pattern base you'll get this.
You'll get fc:3.
And for c, you'll get f3.
You can see that's the same thing.
Then for this particular a m
conditional FP-tree you might,
you just take a c,
you say c's that means a m c or c a m.
Their conditional pattern
base is only f:3.
You get this.
Then you can, you can dump all
the patterns, you know, like this.
For single branch, essentially that's the
same thing, you'll dump all the patterns.
Like all the possible combinations,
they are all three.
Okay.
You probably can see,
if you get a single prefix pass,
you actually can partition
this into two parts.
Like this pass, you can mine and
this part you can mine it too.
Then you can just concatenate
the pattern results.
What about this tree?
Can that fit in the main memory?
If it cannot fit in the memory,
we can use database projection.
That means we project the database
based on the patterns.
Based on single item set, okay?
So, then we can construct and
mine this tree for each project database.
So we can have parallel projection, or
partition projection,
two different methods.
The parallel projection means,
for this one, you will get a.
F4 project database and
f3 project database.
For example, for this first string
you'll see g h suppose it's not
frequent only f, f's are frequent.
You'll get f4's project database,
you get f2, f3.
Okay, then f3's projected base you get f2,
that's a one and
every one of these projected database
is independent of the others so
you can mine them in parallel, but then
you also can have partition projection.
Projected the general philosophy is for
each string, you only put into one place.
For example, this one contains f 4,
you only put f 2 or
f 3 but you don't put this f
2 to f 3 projected database.
When you finish mine this f 4.
When you do this projection,
then you think this one is related
to f 3 you will put one into f 3.
Okay.
So that's a, just a different choices.
You know, for different partition.
Or parallel projection.
I, it's just different
way of implement it.
Thank you
[MUSIC]