[SOUND].
>> Hi, in this final session
of this lecture we're going to
discuss mining closed patterns.
As we already know before,
closed pattern is a compact form but
it's a lot less compression
of frequent patterns.
So mining this closed item sets
is very interesting and useful.
And with pattern growth approach
there is one interesting method,
would be better to call it CLOSET+.
Let's look at this CLOSET+,
how to develop efficient,
direct mining of closed item sets.
So let's look at this
transaction database,
it contains only four transactions and
these are the items in these transactions.
Suppose a minimum support is two,
we would be able to get these
as frequent items sets.
And based on this we can work up
the F-list, like the following, okay?
Now we look at,
you know, an interesting method of
develop called itemset merging, okay?
The philosophy can be represented
using this example, okay?
Let's look at these project database.
For these project database, we will
have acf, ef, and acf based on this.
You can see this project database will get
a-c-d-e-f and acf, but the interesting
thing is acf happens in every
transaction projecting in this database.
Acf have the same support as d.
In that case, we can grab acf out
from acfd project database,
which contains only one item, e.
It is not frequent.
Therefore, we will be able to get acfd,
support is two, it's the final result.
This method itemset merging.
Simply said, says,
if Y appears in every occurrence of X,
then items in Y is merged with X.
Now the X is d, and the Y is acf.
Acf occurs in every occurrence of X,
which is d.
Then we will merge acfd together to
form a more, you know, compressed form.
That means you can mine
that all these immediately.
Okay, so this is more efficient.
Actually there are many
tricks developed in CLOSET+.
For example, hybrid tree projection.
We use bottom-up physical tree-projection,
top-down pseudo tree-projection,
there's a one technical,
sub-itemset pruning,
itemset skipping,
efficient subset testing.
But I'm not going to get into the details.
For details, you can read this paper.
Okay.
So finally I'll summarize
the recommended readings.
These are all classical papers
you know algorithm, you know,
algorithm mining and the, you know, the
further improvement of algorithm mining.
Then we have vertical methods,
we have FP-growth methods and
we have CLOSET+ methods.
So finally there's an interesting
survey article called
Frequent Pattern Mining Algorithms
which contain many more
algorithms covered in this lecture.
If you have interest in,
go ahead and read this chapter.
[MUSIC]